Preliminary Guide to the Project ABC (A Better Chance) Duke University Program Records, 1966 - 1969
Duke University. University Archives
Project ABC (A Better Chance) Duke University Program records 1966 - 1969
Project ABC (Duke University)
4.0 linear feet Extent: 4000 Items
Duke University. University Archives
Project ABC (A Better Chance) began at Dartmouth College in 1964, as a summer program to prepare academically-gifted, underprivileged and minority students to attend independent college preparatory schools. In 1966, Duke University partnered with Project ABC, and conducted intensive, eight-week summer sessions for boys with the goal of easing the transition from public school to private school. Records contain reports, financial materials, and correspondence generated or maintained by Project ABC at Duke University. The bulk of the collection consists of student applications to the ABC program and prep school progress reports. Materials range in date from 1966 to 1969. English.
RL.01328
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Project ABC (A Better Chance) Duke University Program Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1971.
Historical Note
Project ABC (A Better Chance) began at Dartmouth College in 1964, as a summer program to prepare academically-gifted, underprivileged and minority students to attend independent college preparatory schools. In 1966, Duke University partnered with Project ABC, and conducted intensive, eight-week summer sessions for boys with the goal of easing the transition from public school to private school.
Collection Overview
Records contain reports, financial materials, and correspondence generated or maintained by Project ABC at Duke University. The bulk of the collection consists of student applications to the ABC program and prep school progress reports. Materials range in date from 1966 to 1969.
Arrangement
Roughly arranged in chronological order.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be accessed under the following subject headings in the Duke University Libraries online catalog.
Duke University -- History; Project ABC (Duke University); Project ABC; Minority students -- Education; College preparatory schools; Preparatory school students
Preliminary Description of the Collection
- Container List:
  - Students, 1966 (Box 1-2)
  - Accounts, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Prep school progress reports, 1966
  - Director's report, 1966
  - Students, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Administration, 1966
  - Students, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Administration, 1967
  - Accounts, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Staff and faculty, 1967
  - Students, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Accounts, 1968
  - Administration, 1968
  - Staff and faculty, 1968
  - Students, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Accounts, 1969
  - Administration, 1969
  - Staff and faculty, 1969